<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Celonis hacks</title>
    <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Celonis hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 11:42:09 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand how Tables are joined in Data Model</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-19-understand-how-tables-are-joined-in-data-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 11:42:09 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-19-understand-how-tables-are-joined-in-data-model/</guid>
      <description>In the Understand Difference between Dimension and KPI post, I mentioned that Columns used as dimensions and KPIs are inplicitly joined based on data model, but I did not mention how to join tables in data model. Today I would like to say about it.
Celonis Data Model support snowflake schema that consists of multiple tables, each table pair join as 1:N relationship. Normally activity table is top of N side and dimension tables including case table are bottom of 1 side as pyramid hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate Multi Dimensional KPIs</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-12-calculate-multi-dimentional-kpis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 13:20:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-12-calculate-multi-dimentional-kpis/</guid>
      <description>In the last post Recognize Record to Calculate KPI, I showed issue of count duplication when I merged two different dimentional KPIs. Today I will tell how to calculate it correctly.
I will start from changing OLAP table to hide USER_TYPE and ACTIVITY_EN for calculating KPIs grouped by customer master. And I filtered by customer K1 as previous post. Finally I added SUM function to both Rework Time and Reminder Time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognize Record to Calculate KPI</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-05-recognize-record-to-calculate-kpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:34:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-05-recognize-record-to-calculate-kpi/</guid>
      <description>Using Pull up function, you can calculate various kind of KPIs. I would like to tell in this post is taking care the record (dimensions) to calculate each KPI especially when you unite multiple KPIs to same component.
In this example, I will use Order to Cash process again and first I would like to estiamate time of rework. Definition of rework Activity is same as previous post, and one more condition is it happens by manual user (USER_TYPE = &#39;A&#39;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Pull up function as Subquery</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-29-use-pull-up-function-as-subquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 13:04:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-29-use-pull-up-function-as-subquery/</guid>
      <description>In the last post Determine First Time Right by Pull up function, I broke down PQL of FTR step by step. Today I will explain more complex KPI in similar way. By the way you may know Subquery that enables to pass result of SQL to parts of another SQL. PQL can also do similar things by Pull up function.
In this post, for example I would like to calculate Average rework count after Delivery in Order to Cash process, and definition of rework is same as previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determine First Time Right by Pull up function</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-22-determine-first-time-right-by-pull-up-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 16:31:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-22-determine-first-time-right-by-pull-up-function/</guid>
      <description>As a first example of Pull up function, I will show you First Time Right (FTR) that means process without rework activities (link).
To determine FTR, first I should determine rework activities, in this example I decided they are started from Change. PQL to judge such string is &amp;quot;_CEL_P2P_ACTIVITIES_EN&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;ACTIVITY_EN&amp;quot; LIKE &#39;Change %&#39;, using wildcard % after Change and use keyword LIKE for pattern matching.
Next step is counting rework activities in each case (&amp;quot;EKPO&amp;quot;, Purchase Order item table in this example) by pull up function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand mechanism of Pull up function</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-15-understand-mechanism-of-pull-up-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 10:00:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-15-understand-mechanism-of-pull-up-function/</guid>
      <description>Pull up aggregation function, called PU function, like PU_COUNT, PU_SUM, PU_AVG, PU_MAX, PU_MIN looks similar to Standard aggregation function like COUNT, SUM, AVG, MAX, MIN. In Celonis, it is important to understand that output of PU function is not KPI but dimension. You can see Understand Difference between Dimension and KPI.
If you know about SQL, you can imagine that PU function is similar to window function in SQL. As other functions, PU functions add dynamic column in grouping table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize Process Explorer</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-08-customize-process-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 09:15:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-08-customize-process-explorer/</guid>
      <description>Process explorer in Celonis Analysis is default application to analyze process. First you can see main process pattern (called happy path), count of each step (activity) and count of path between two steps (connection). You can show minor activities and connections, or switch throughput time instead of count of connection.
I think there are two ways to customize Process explorer.
 Change activity name Add more KPI against activity / connection  Change activity name If you want to add detail information to each activity, you can change activity dimension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Difference between Dimension and KPI</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-01-understand-difference-between-dimension-and-kpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 15:25:08 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-01-understand-difference-between-dimension-and-kpi/</guid>
      <description>If you are beginner of creating Celonis Analysis, I believe you will first create OLAP table to understand how Celonis PQL works with data model. Points are,
 Dimensions are grouping key to calculate KPI, normally they are string (character) columns KPIs are calculated figures based on specific numeric columns, or count of rows of any columns, it must be numeric value in either cases Columns used as dimensions and KPIs are inplicitly joined based on data model  Below screenshot is the quite simple example to show Dimension, KPI, and data model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>