<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content-CLI on Celonis hacks</title>
    <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/tags/content-cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content-CLI on Celonis hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 08:54:10 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/tags/content-cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute Periodic ETL Automatically</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2022-04-30-execute-periodic-etl-automatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 08:54:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2022-04-30-execute-periodic-etl-automatically/</guid>
      <description>Until last post Validate Data Model by Studio Analysis, I completed creating ETL programs in Data Integration. But this is still test product because this programs are executed manually by operator. In this post, I would like to share the final piece of Data Integration, how to run ETL programs automatically after production release.
There are several ways to achieve automatic ETL, for example in my production system I am using scheduler in Machine Learning Workbench to trigger Jupyter Notebook, then operate Data Integration via Pycelonis (Python API for Celonis EMS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share my Analysis by Content-CLI</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-14-share-my-analysis-by-content-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 13:33:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-14-share-my-analysis-by-content-cli/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was thinking how to share my work with you not only blog post but experience by live environment. Today I would like to tell how to reproduce my Analysis to your environment by Content-CLI. Content-CLI is used to copy programs between Celonis environments via backup file. I created backup file and upload to public repository. So you can download it and reproduce my program in your environment.
First you need to open your training environment if you do not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>