<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extractor on Celonis hacks</title>
    <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/tags/extractor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extractor on Celonis hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 08:39:24 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/tags/extractor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at Data Transfer Process by Data Job Log</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-11-20-look-at-data-transfer-process-by-data-job-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 08:39:24 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-11-20-look-at-data-transfer-process-by-data-job-log/</guid>
      <description>Last week I posted Connect to Celonis and Bring Back Instruction to look at how Extractor works to connect between Celonis and Postgres. This week I would like to extract data from Postgres and look at data transfer process by data job log.
In the Event Collection, I create new Data Job with Data Connection I created last week, then create new extraction task. In the next screen I add new table public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Celonis and Bring Back Instruction</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-11-13-connect-to-celonis-and-bring-back-instruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 10:19:49 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-11-13-connect-to-celonis-and-bring-back-instruction/</guid>
      <description>From last week I started Event Collection series and posted Run Extractor on Your Local Machine to prepare for my Extractor and Postgres database. Today I will start using Extractor and show you the mechanism to extract data safely.
From this week I will start Extractor and Postgres by next two steps (same as last week).
 Open VS code and open terminal at celonis-postgres folder. Enter docker-compose up in VS code terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Extractor on Your Local Machine</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-11-06-run-extractor-on-your-local-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 09:59:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-11-06-run-extractor-on-your-local-machine/</guid>
      <description>From this week I would like to explain my experience regarding Event Collection functions (Extraction, Transformation, Load etc.). To do this, I try to create sample source systems and build code in Celonis training environment.
As first topic, I would like to explain on premise Extractor, that is in the middle between your source systems (SAP, Oracle etc.) and Celonis EMS and support transferring data. By the way, because I do not want to pay licence of source systems for this blog, I would like to use open source Postgres database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>