<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Celonis hacks</title>
    <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Celonis hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 13:16:26 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Use BIND function to enable multiple DOMAIN_TABLE</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-09-11-use-bind-function-to-enable-multiple-domain-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 13:16:26 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-09-11-use-bind-function-to-enable-multiple-domain-table/</guid>
      <description>Variant Explorer is the major Celonis Analytical view to find process pattern by GUI operation. Of course I used it many times and enjoyed it at first, and found that I had a lot of effort to filter on and off to observe process. Today I would like to create collective list of variant to see major process KPI&amp;rsquo;s. Also I would like to show you BIND function that is difficult to understand but quite convenient if you know it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert count unit of KPI by COUNT DISTINCT</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-09-04-convert-count-unit-of-kpi-by-count-distinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 09:06:11 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-09-04-convert-count-unit-of-kpi-by-count-distinct/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was asked to convert count unit of some KPI (that returns 1 or 0) from delivery item to delivery document (convert if all items in the document are 1 then document KPI is 1, else 0). In this case delivery document and item columns are stored at Activity table like this post&amp;rsquo;s third topic. I already used DOMAIN_TABLE to group activity record by delivery item then calculate KPI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count rows of Tables in various way</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-28-count-rows-of-tables-in-various-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 11:11:45 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-28-count-rows-of-tables-in-various-way/</guid>
      <description>Counting rows of tables is frequently used so we are not aware about how to do it. But sometimes I got stuck to do it so I would like to deep dive this topic today.
For today&amp;rsquo;s demo case I use P2P data model and three tables, header EKKO (key columns are MANDT/EBELN), item EKPO (MANDT/EBELN/EBELP) and activity. Also I used sum of item Net value. Below screen is the result of today&amp;rsquo;s demo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Conditional Function to return 1 or NULL</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-21-make-conditional-function-to-return-1-or-null/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 10:42:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-21-make-conditional-function-to-return-1-or-null/</guid>
      <description>Previously I posted Handle NULL efficiently in Aggregation Function and discussed how to unite formula of COUNT, SUM, AVG functions. Today I will create boolean function and use it for conditional aggregation.
Imagine you would like to calculate net value of Sales Order (VBAP.NETWR_CONVERTED) in O2C process, but there are some conditons to calculate it. First condition is that sales order is active, means rejection reason column (VBAP.ABGRU) is not set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share my Analysis by Content-CLI</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-14-share-my-analysis-by-content-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 13:33:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-14-share-my-analysis-by-content-cli/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was thinking how to share my work with you not only blog post but experience by live environment. Today I would like to tell how to reproduce my Analysis to your environment by Content-CLI. Content-CLI is used to copy programs between Celonis environments via backup file. I created backup file and upload to public repository. So you can download it and reproduce my program in your environment.
First you need to open your training environment if you do not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Matrix of Throughput Time by Pivot Table</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-07-create-matrix-of-throughput-time-by-pivot-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 14:07:40 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-08-07-create-matrix-of-throughput-time-by-pivot-table/</guid>
      <description>At the previous post of Customize Process Explorer, I showed how to determine throughput time between two activities. This KPI is visible when expanding Process Explorer, but font size of Process Explorer become smaller and smaller when expanding connections, so it is difficult to grasp overview of throughput time.
Until previous post, I usually used OLAP table to show the list of KPI value. Of course it is good enough to grasp overview, but today I used different component &amp;lsquo;Pivot Table&amp;rsquo; to show KPI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Additional Entry to Button Dropdown</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-31-create-additional-entry-to-button-dropdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 10:00:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-31-create-additional-entry-to-button-dropdown/</guid>
      <description>I looked at the Celopeers post that had issue when variable input is blank (NULL) then PQL using this variable had error. Work around solution is to use &amp;lt;% if(Target != &amp;quot;&amp;quot;) { %&amp;gt; FILTER &amp;quot;table&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;column&amp;quot; IN (&amp;lt;%=Target%&amp;gt;); &amp;lt;% } %&amp;gt; (Target is variable) then skip FILTER execution if variable is null.
I already used this work around but I also felt troublesome in two points. First is this is not officially documented so myself need to instruct to my colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categorize and Name Activity</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-24-categorize-and-name-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 10:47:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-24-categorize-and-name-activity/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post Transform Source System Tables to Minimize Data Model Tables, I recommended to convert some kind of source system tables to Activity. Today I focus on Activity and would like to share my way how to categorize and name Activity.
First point is to split Activity name to two parts, more general part and detail part. For example, in SAP ECC or S4HANA Order to Cash process, general Activity name is Create Sales Order when data committed in VA01 transaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform Source System Tables to Minimize Data Model Tables</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-17-transform-source-system-tables-to-minimize-data-model-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 13:24:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-17-transform-source-system-tables-to-minimize-data-model-tables/</guid>
      <description>In the last part of previous post Utilize N-M relationship between Activity and Dimension Tables, I said just mimicing source system&amp;rsquo;s table structure to data model is not useful for Celonis data model. Also I feel loading time to data model is exponentially long when one more table is added. So minimizing data model table is good practice especially for real time analytics.
In case of SAP Order to Cash (O2C) scenario, case table is sales order item (VBAP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilize N-M relationship between Activity and Dimension Tables</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-10-utilize-n-m-relationship-between-activity-and-dimension-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 10:08:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-10-utilize-n-m-relationship-between-activity-and-dimension-tables/</guid>
      <description>When you determine data model structure by yourself, basically you should follow snowflake schema writtern in Understand how Tables are joined in Data Model. From case table perspective, n side is case table, and 1 side is another dimension table. On the other hand, activity table is the first case that 1 side is case table. If you determine second dimension table that 1 side is case table, please note that you can not use both activity and that dimension table at once because those tables are N-M relationship via case table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintain Saved Formulas effectively</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-03-maintain-saved-formulas-effectively/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 21:25:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-07-03-maintain-saved-formulas-effectively/</guid>
      <description>In the last post Handle NULL efficiently in Aggregation Function, I used saved formulas to split long and complex PQL to reusable components. Today I would like to share my best practice to use saved formulas.
For example I would like to ananlyze throughput time between arbitrary two activities. As below screenshot I created three dropdown buttons, switching time unit (sec, min, hour, day etc.) and two activities (from / to).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handle NULL efficiently in Aggregation Function</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-26-handle-null-efficiently-in-aggregation-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 09:37:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-26-handle-null-efficiently-in-aggregation-function/</guid>
      <description>I looked at many PQLs that can be simplified if they know about NULL handling well. Today I would like to tell how to handle NULL efficiently in Aggregation Functions (COUNT,SUM,AVG etc.).
Today I would like to use O2C process to explain my case. I determined KPI Send Invoice within a day after Ship Goods, because sales company will Ship Goods then should Send Invoice immediately.
Same as previous posts, first I would like to create OLAP table to look into the cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand how Tables are joined in Data Model</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-19-understand-how-tables-are-joined-in-data-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 11:42:09 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-19-understand-how-tables-are-joined-in-data-model/</guid>
      <description>In the Understand Difference between Dimension and KPI post, I mentioned that Columns used as dimensions and KPIs are inplicitly joined based on data model, but I did not mention how to join tables in data model. Today I would like to say about it.
Celonis Data Model support snowflake schema that consists of multiple tables, each table pair join as 1:N relationship. Normally activity table is top of N side and dimension tables including case table are bottom of 1 side as pyramid hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate Multi Dimensional KPIs</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-12-calculate-multi-dimentional-kpis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 13:20:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-12-calculate-multi-dimentional-kpis/</guid>
      <description>In the last post Recognize Record to Calculate KPI, I showed issue of count duplication when I merged two different dimentional KPIs. Today I will tell how to calculate it correctly.
I will start from changing OLAP table to hide USER_TYPE and ACTIVITY_EN for calculating KPIs grouped by customer master. And I filtered by customer K1 as previous post. Finally I added SUM function to both Rework Time and Reminder Time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognize Record to Calculate KPI</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-05-recognize-record-to-calculate-kpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:34:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-06-05-recognize-record-to-calculate-kpi/</guid>
      <description>Using Pull up function, you can calculate various kind of KPIs. I would like to tell in this post is taking care the record (dimensions) to calculate each KPI especially when you unite multiple KPIs to same component.
In this example, I will use Order to Cash process again and first I would like to estiamate time of rework. Definition of rework Activity is same as previous post, and one more condition is it happens by manual user (USER_TYPE = &#39;A&#39;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Pull up function as Subquery</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-29-use-pull-up-function-as-subquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 13:04:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-29-use-pull-up-function-as-subquery/</guid>
      <description>In the last post Determine First Time Right by Pull up function, I broke down PQL of FTR step by step. Today I will explain more complex KPI in similar way. By the way you may know Subquery that enables to pass result of SQL to parts of another SQL. PQL can also do similar things by Pull up function.
In this post, for example I would like to calculate Average rework count after Delivery in Order to Cash process, and definition of rework is same as previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determine First Time Right by Pull up function</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-22-determine-first-time-right-by-pull-up-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 16:31:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-22-determine-first-time-right-by-pull-up-function/</guid>
      <description>As a first example of Pull up function, I will show you First Time Right (FTR) that means process without rework activities (link).
To determine whether each case is FTR or not, first I should determine rework activities, then judge if each case has rework activities or not. In this example I determined that rework activity name is started from Change. PQL to find such a string pattern is Change %, using wildcard % after Change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand mechanism of Pull up function</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-15-understand-mechanism-of-pull-up-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 10:00:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-15-understand-mechanism-of-pull-up-function/</guid>
      <description>Pull up aggregation function, called PU function, like PU_COUNT, PU_SUM, PU_AVG, PU_MAX, PU_MIN looks similar to Standard aggregation function like COUNT, SUM, AVG, MAX, MIN. In Celonis, it is important to understand that output of PU function is not KPI but dimension. You can see Understand Difference between Dimension and KPI.
If you know about SQL, you can imagine that PU function is similar to window function in SQL. As other functions, PU functions add dynamic column in grouping table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize Process Explorer</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-08-customize-process-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 09:15:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-08-customize-process-explorer/</guid>
      <description>Process explorer in Celonis Analysis is default application to analyze process. First you can see main process pattern (called happy path), count of each step (activity) and count of path between two steps (connection). You can show minor activities and connections, or switch throughput time instead of count of connection.
I think there are two ways to customize Process explorer.
 Change activity name Add more KPI against activity / connection  Change activity name If you want to add detail information to each activity, you can change activity dimension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Difference between Dimension and KPI</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-01-understand-difference-between-dimension-and-kpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 15:25:08 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/posts/2021-05-01-understand-difference-between-dimension-and-kpi/</guid>
      <description>If you are beginner of creating Celonis Analysis, I believe you will first create OLAP table to understand how Celonis PQL works with data model. Points are,
 Dimensions are grouping key to calculate KPI, normally they are string (character) columns KPIs are calculated figures based on specific numeric columns, or count of rows of any columns, it must be numeric value in either cases Columns used as dimensions and KPIs are inplicitly joined based on data model  Below screenshot is the quite simple example to show Dimension, KPI, and data model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this site</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Greeting Hello, I am Kazuhiko Takata, called Kaz. I am working as freelance consultant from 2005, especially technical expert of SAP and Celonis. Please see my LinkedIn profile if you are interested.
Objective I would like to share what I learned to catch up latest Celonis technical topics and finally become Celonis Data Engineer. When I started Celonis career in 2019, I developed Celonis programs from scratch to analyze SAP process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaztakata.github.io/celonis-hacks/search/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>